<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on private void</title><link>https://weirdaemon.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on private void</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 12:53:40 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://weirdaemon.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Begin again</title><link>https://weirdaemon.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 12:53:40 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://weirdaemon.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid><description>Bruno had rollmop herrings as a starter. &amp;lsquo;Now&amp;rsquo;, he thought, &amp;lsquo;anything is possible.&amp;rsquo; He had hardly done so when he realised that he was wrong. [&amp;hellip;] Rollmops were clearly not the solution, but then again, had he chosen sea bass with fennel it would have been no different.
&amp;ndash;Michel Houellebecq, Atomised
Increasingly I feel like nothing is possible. Typically if you ask me what the substance of my day-to-day experience is, I&amp;rsquo;m probably going to tell you &amp;rsquo;nothing&amp;rsquo;.</description><content>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Bruno had rollmop herrings as a starter. &amp;lsquo;Now&amp;rsquo;, he thought, &amp;lsquo;anything is possible.&amp;rsquo; He had hardly done so when he realised that he was wrong. [&amp;hellip;] Rollmops were clearly not the solution, but then again, had he chosen sea bass with fennel it would have been no different.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&amp;ndash;Michel Houellebecq,&lt;/em> Atomised&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Increasingly I feel like nothing is possible. Typically if you ask me what the substance of my day-to-day experience is, I&amp;rsquo;m probably going to tell you &amp;rsquo;nothing&amp;rsquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m big on exaggeration, but it would be true to say that my life seems to have the quality of a dream, and I&amp;rsquo;m not certain it&amp;rsquo;s a good one. I have a creeping sense that I&amp;rsquo;ve done something wrong, or that I&amp;rsquo;m being continually pursued. Social life is actually painful to a greater or lesser extent, and I have a sense that my consciousness is less a limitless and luminous space than a cast-iron walnut shell out of which I can only catch glimpses of human experience. I knew something had to change when I became conscious that I&amp;rsquo;d invoked Alasdair Gray by literally mumbling the word &amp;lsquo;useless&amp;rsquo; to myself as I walked down the street recently. I feel it&amp;rsquo;s long past time to make some sense of this bizarre situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On some level it&amp;rsquo;s fair enough that this is the case. It&amp;rsquo;s been almost two years since my life took on a positively nightmarish quality, just in time for the last two years of my bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree. I was alternately completely alone and surrounded by strangers; thunderously hammering out a program at the last minute and frittering my time away on the internet; lying wide awake in bed and lying on a low-pile carpet in the computer science building, exhausted from days without sleep. Often the only sensory input I was conscious of was my fingertips on a mouse button or keycap. It was the anaesthetic life, and I answered the question of whether it was worth living by resenting it and wishing it gone. And now it &lt;em>is&lt;/em> gone, I want to start again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A daemon is a program that runs in the background without requiring any intervention from the user. Ideally you want your demons to also be daemons: they tick along relatively harmlessly in the background and don&amp;rsquo;t present themselves to the user by causing chaos in your life and making marks that you can never take back. I&amp;rsquo;m presently looking at trying to make this the case, and part of that effort is this blog; if it makes me less dour in person, less likely to miss an opportunity to actually love those I nominally love, then by all means I&amp;rsquo;ll put my thoughts to you instead of the people in my actual life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll let you know how it goes.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>